<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='yes'?>
<w:document xmlns:wpc="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingCanvas" xmlns:mo="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/mac/office/2008/main" xmlns:mc="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/markup-compatibility/2006" xmlns:mv="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:mac:vml" xmlns:o="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:office" xmlns:r="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/relationships" xmlns:m="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/math" xmlns:v="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:vml" xmlns:wp14="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingDrawing" xmlns:wp="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/drawingml/2006/wordprocessingDrawing" xmlns:w10="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:word" xmlns:w="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/wordprocessingml/2006/main" xmlns:w14="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordml" xmlns:wpg="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingGroup" xmlns:wpi="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingInk" xmlns:wne="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2006/wordml" xmlns:wps="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/word/2010/wordprocessingShape" mc:Ignorable="w14 wp14"><w:body><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Title"/><w:jc w:val="center"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>ALPHADUCATION NEWSLETTER CONTENT FILE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Subtitle"/><w:jc w:val="center"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>Issue: WP-008 | Series: The Weekly Proof | Title: Spaced Repetition: The Most Underused Tool in Mathematics Education</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION A+B — MASTHEAD &amp; METADATA</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">TAGLINE: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:rPr><w:i/></w:rPr><w:t>What feels forgotten may be the only thing finally learned.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">DATE: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:rPr><w:color w:val="E95924"/><w:highlight w:val="yellow"/></w:rPr><w:t>[Leave blank — to be filled by editor]</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">READING_TIME: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>≈ 10 min read</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">COMPLEXITY: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Discover</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">TOPIC_TAGS: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Memory, Mathematics Practice, Retrieval</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">EDITOR_NAME: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>The Alphaducation Team</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION C — OPENING LETTER</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>A student can finish ten algebra questions on Tuesday, score eight out of ten, and still sit on Friday as if the method belongs to someone else. Teachers see this every week. We explain carefully, students imitate well, and the lesson feels successful—until time asks its own question.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>That gap between performance now and memory later is not a small technical issue in mathematics. It sits at the heart of the subject. Mathematics is cumulative. A forgotten identity weakens later trigonometry. A shaky fraction idea returns inside algebra. A method that looked secure in the lesson can quietly disappear before it ever becomes usable knowledge.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>The spacing literature matters because it names something many classrooms feel but do not always design for: learning often happens in the revisiting, not only in the first encounter. The question is not whether students were once shown the idea. The question is whether the idea can still be retrieved when the next idea depends on it. That is where this issue begins.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:jc w:val="right"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:rPr><w:i/></w:rPr><w:t>— The Alphaducation Team</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION D — MAIN FEATURE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>FEATURE_TITLE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="222222"/><w:sz w:val="26"/></w:rPr><w:t>Why the Best Mathematics Lesson Might Begin After Class Ends</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>FEATURE_DECK</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:i/></w:rPr><w:t>Spacing does not make mathematics easier in the moment; it makes it stay.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>FEATURE_OPENING</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Many mathematics lessons are built as if mastery should be visible by the end of the hour. A concept is explained, a few worked examples are completed, then students practise a block of nearly identical questions. By the last item, fluency usually rises. The danger is that this rise can be misread.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Pashler et al. (2007) argued that instruction should be organised around what improves later learning, not only what looks smooth during initial study. The spacing literature pushes the same point more sharply: when practice is distributed over time rather than massed into one sitting, later retention improves. In mathematics, that matters more than in many subjects because forgotten knowledge does not remain isolated. It becomes the hidden weakness inside the next topic.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>Mathematical Lens — Mathematics Remembers in Layers</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Mathematics is not just a list of topics. It is a dependency structure. Later ideas lean on earlier ones even when the earlier ones are no longer being named. A student solving quadratic equations is also relying on symbol sense, sign control, factorisation habits, and comfort with algebraic transformation. That is why forgetting in mathematics is rarely local. It travels.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>This is also why blocked practice can be misleading. Rohrer and Taylor (2007) showed that when problem types are shuffled rather than grouped by method, students learn better. Part of the reason is mathematical, not merely mnemonic: students must identify what kind of problem they are facing instead of repeating the same routine while it is still warm. Mixed practice spaces repetitions of the same method and forces discrimination, which is a central mathematical act.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Lyle, Bego, Hopkins, Hieb, and Ralston (2020) make the point even more directly for mathematics. In their precalculus work, both doing more practice and spacing that practice helped within-semester retention, but across-semester retention benefited exclusively from increasing spacing. That result matters because mathematics is judged over long horizons. A method that survives until next semester is educationally different from a method that only survives until the homework is submitted.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Murray, Horner, and Göbel (2025) strengthen the case while also disciplining it. Their meta-analysis found a real small-to-medium advantage for spaced over massed mathematics practice. That is large enough to matter in a cumulative subject, especially when small gains compound across units. But they also warn against exaggeration: the retrieval-versus-restudy effect in mathematics is not yet conclusively established. So the honest mathematical claim is not that every memory-based technique transforms math learning. It is that revisiting mathematical content across time reliably helps it last.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>The French didactic perspective adds a useful caution. Artigue and Trouche (2021) remind us that mathematics education is not only about storing information efficiently. It is about students entering relations with mathematical objects, representations, techniques, and situations. A good spaced design therefore does more than repeat facts. It reopens structures, reconnects representations, and places old knowledge inside new mathematical work.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>FEATURE_PULLQUOTE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:ind w:left="360" w:right="360"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:rPr><w:i/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t>“A worksheet can prove that a method was visible five minutes ago; only time can show whether it became part of the student’s mathematical world.”</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>Pedagogical Lens — Designing Return, Not Just Coverage</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>For teachers, spacing is less a gadget than a planning principle. Pashler et al. (2007) recommended spacing key course content as a core instructional move, which means important ideas should not disappear once the unit page is turned. The practical shift is modest but powerful: instead of teaching a topic once and reviewing it only before the test, we build structured returns into ordinary teaching.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Those returns can be simple. A cumulative warm-up places one question from yesterday, one from last week, and one from a prior unit at the start of class. A short Friday quiz can include current content alongside older core ideas. Homework can be interleaved so that students must choose a method, not just perform the one most recently demonstrated. None of this requires a dramatic timetable change. It requires a different image of what practice is for.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>The challenge is that good learning can look worse before it looks better. Lyle, Bego, Ralston, and Immekus (2022) found that spaced retrieval in calculus improved end-of-semester retention even though practice performance could dip early on. This is the classroom version of desirable difficulty. If we judge a routine only by how fluent students feel during the first attempt, we may discard the very conditions that make the knowledge retrievable later.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Riopel and McMullin (2021) add something teachers often sense immediately: motivation matters. A revisiting schedule that feels random, punitive, or endlessly accumulative can exhaust students. A better design is brief, predictable, and proportionate. Students should experience return as part of how mathematics works, not as evidence that they have failed to learn it the first time.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Tools must also be used with restraint. Dunlosky et al. (2013) rated distributed practice and practice testing highly, but a technique with strong evidence can still be badly applied. Flashcards and spaced apps are useful for notation, vocabulary, identities, formulas, and canonical facts. They are much weaker as stand-alone tools for proof, modelling, or rich problem solving. The teacher’s task is not to turn mathematics into a memory game. It is to decide what should be made quickly retrievable so that deeper thinking has something stable to stand on.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>Epistemological Lens — What Time Counts as Knowledge</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Spacing matters because it forces a deeper question than "Did students understand the explanation?" It asks what we are willing to count as learning. If knowledge vanishes as soon as the worked example leaves the board, then the lesson may have produced successful performance without durable possession.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>That distinction is not merely technical. It changes the meaning of teaching. Musial, Pradère, and Tricot (2011) argue that pedagogy should be designed in light of how learning actually unfolds. From that perspective, time is not an afterthought added at revision stage; it is part of the structure of the learning situation itself.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>This is where the issue becomes quietly philosophical. A subject begins to look different when we judge it by what remains available after delay. In mathematics, spaced return is a way of respecting the fact that understanding is not only something shown once. It is something that survives, reappears, and can be used again under new conditions.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>FEATURE_SYNTHESIS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Seen mathematically, spacing protects a cumulative subject from silent erosion. Seen pedagogically, it changes everyday routines more than it changes grand theory. Seen epistemologically, it asks us to stop confusing immediate fluency with lasting knowledge. The strongest version of the claim is also the most modest one: if we want mathematics to remain usable, we have to design for its return.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION E — THE ALPHA PROOF BOX</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>PROOF_CITATION</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Murray, E., Horner, A. J., &amp; Göbel, S. M. (2025). A meta-analytic review of the effectiveness of spacing and retrieval practice for mathematics learning. Educational Psychology Review, 37, 75. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10648-025-10035-1</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>PROOF_GLOSS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Murray, Horner, and Göbel (2025) provide the best single anchor for this issue because they synthesise mathematics-specific evidence rather than relying on general learning claims alone. Their meta-analysis finds a reliable small-to-medium benefit for spaced over massed mathematics practice, which supports the core argument of this issue. Just as importantly, they avoid overclaiming: the evidence that retrieval outperforms restudy in mathematics is not yet conclusive.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>PROOF_ACCESSIBILITY</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Intermediate</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION F — PRACTITIONER FIELD NOTES</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>FIELD_LEVEL</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>All Levels</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>FIELD_CONTEXT</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>These routines work best when they are brief, predictable, and built into normal teaching rather than added as emergency revision. Their purpose is not to create more pressure. It is to make important mathematics return before it disappears.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>STRATEGY_1 — Mixed-start warm-up</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Open class with three or four short prompts drawn from different time horizons: one from yesterday, one from last week, and one from an older unit. Students retrieve before notes are reopened. This turns the start of the lesson into a memory bridge, not just a settling activity.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Try_this: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Tomorrow, begin with one current question, one recent question, and one older core-skill question on the board.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>STRATEGY_2 — Shuffle the homework</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Avoid long blocks of near-identical questions. Rohrer and Taylor (2007) showed that interleaving improves learning because students must identify the method, not merely continue it. The goal is not confusion for its own sake; it is better mathematical recognition.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Try_this: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Reorder tonight’s assignment so no two adjacent questions use the same procedure.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>STRATEGY_3 — Friday revisit quiz</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Use a short, low-stakes weekly quiz that mixes present and past content. This protects important ideas from becoming one-unit knowledge and gives the teacher better information about what is still alive.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Try_this: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Build a six-question quiz with two items from the current unit, two from the previous one, and two from older essentials.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>STRATEGY_4 — Retrieve before reteach</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Before explaining again, ask students to attempt recall first. Even a ninety-second effort can strengthen later retention and reveal what was actually retained. It also stops re-explanation from replacing thinking.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Try_this: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Before reviewing identities or factorisation, give students ninety seconds to write whatever they can recover without notes.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>STRATEGY_5 — Card only the exacts</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Use flashcards or Anki for content that benefits from exact recall: notation, formulas, theorem statements, terminology, and standard identities. Do not force every kind of mathematical thinking into a card format.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Try_this: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Ask students to make cards only for knowledge they must retrieve quickly and accurately in later work.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>LIMITATIONS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Spacing does not replace first teaching. Students still need explanation, examples, and conceptual sense-making at first encounter. The evidence is stronger for retention of facts, procedures, and recognisable problem types than for proof, modelling, or far transfer, and the ideal spacing schedule still depends on context.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION G — THE ALPHA QUESTION</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>ALPHA_QUESTION</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t>Why do we teach as if learning happens in the lesson, when the evidence suggests it happens after?</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION H — TOOLBOX SPOTLIGHT</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_NAME</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Anki / Spaced Practice Planner</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_TYPE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Digital Tool</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_ONELINER</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>A system that schedules return so students revisit knowledge before it fades completely.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_REVIEW</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Anki operationalises a strong idea: material that is hard to retrieve should return sooner, while stable material can wait longer. Used well, it is especially helpful for notation, formulas, vocabulary, identities, and other exact mathematical knowledge that students need available on demand. A paper-based spaced practice planner can do much of the same work with less technology and more teacher control. The strength lies in the principle more than in the platform.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_BEST_FOR</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:ind w:left="288"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>— Cumulative mathematics courses with many formulas, identities, or definitions</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:ind w:left="288"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>— Independent study habits between lessons</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:ind w:left="288"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>— Teacher-designed revision plans that need predictable revisit points</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_LIMITATIONS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:ind w:left="288"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>— It supports retention; it does not create conceptual understanding by itself.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:ind w:left="288"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>— It fits exact knowledge far better than proof, modelling, or open-ended reasoning.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_RATING_RESEARCH</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>★★★☆☆ — principle-backed, product-thinner</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_RATING_EASE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>★★★☆☆ — easy to access, harder to sustain well</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_RATING_IMPACT</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>★★★★☆ — strong when used selectively</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>TOOL_URL</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>https://apps.ankiweb.net/</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION I — QUICK READS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>QUICK_READ_1</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Tag: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>NEW RESEARCH</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Title: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>A Meta-analytic Review of the Effectiveness of Spacing and Retrieval Practice for Mathematics Learning</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>The clearest recent mathematics-specific map of what is supported, what is modest, and what remains unsettled.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Source: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Murray, E., Horner, A. J., &amp; Göbel, S. M. (2025). Educational Psychology Review, 37, 75. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10648-025-10035-1</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>QUICK_READ_2</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Tag: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>POLICY</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Title: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Organizing Instruction and Study to Improve Student Learning</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>A concise practice guide that translates the spacing literature into usable planning recommendations for classrooms.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Source: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Pashler, H., Bain, P. M., Bottge, B. A., Graesser, A., Koedinger, K., McDaniel, M., &amp; Metcalfe, J. (2007). Institute of Education Sciences. https://ies.ed.gov/ncee/wwc/Docs/PracticeGuide/20072004.pdf</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>QUICK_READ_3</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Tag: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>DEBATE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Title: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Effets d’espacement et de répétition en contexte scolaire</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>A French-language piece that keeps the spacing discussion close to school reality, especially motivation and implementation.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Source: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Riopel, M., &amp; McMullin, S. O. (2021). Neuroéducation, 7(1), 13–19. https://doi.org/10.24046/neuroed.20210701.13</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>QUICK_READ_4</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Tag: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>BOOK</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Title: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Powerful Teaching: Unleash the Science of Learning</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>A practical bridge between research on retrieval and spacing and the daily routines teachers can actually build.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Source: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Agarwal, P. K., &amp; Bain, P. M. (2019). Jossey-Bass. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119549031</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading3"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>QUICK_READ_5</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Tag: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>TOOL</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Title: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Anki — Official Documentation</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Description: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Useful when you want to see how a popular spaced-repetition tool structures return over time.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">Source: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Anki. https://apps.ankiweb.net/</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION J — GLOSSARY CORNER</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>GLOSSARY_TERM</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Retrieval Practice</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>GLOSSARY_PRONUNCIATION</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>/rɪˈtriːvəl ˈpræk.tɪs/</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>GLOSSARY_FIELD</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Experimental psychology / memory research</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>GLOSSARY_DEFINITION</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Retrieval practice is the act of recalling previously learned information from memory rather than looking at it again. In education, it matters because the recall attempt itself can strengthen later learning. The key idea is that remembering is not only a test of learning; it can also be part of learning.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>GLOSSARY_ETYMOLOGY</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Retrieval comes from the verb retrieve, via Old French roots meaning to find again or recover.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>GLOSSARY_IN_CLASS</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>In class, retrieval practice appears when students answer from memory before notes are reopened, complete a cumulative warm-up, or revisit older content on a short quiz. Its value is greatest when the recall is deliberate, brief, and connected to later use.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>GLOSSARY_CONFUSED_WITH</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Often confused with the testing effect: retrieval practice is the activity, while the testing effect is the observed benefit that can follow from that activity.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading2"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>GLOSSARY_KEY_REF</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>Agarwal, P. K., Nunes, L. D., &amp; Blunt, J. R. (2021). Retrieval practice consistently benefits student learning: A systematic review of applied research in schools and classrooms. Educational Psychology Review, 33, 1409–1453. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10648-021-09595-9</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION K — REFERENCES</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">1. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Agarwal, P. K., &amp; Bain, P. M. (2019). Powerful teaching: Unleash the science of learning. Jossey-Bass. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119549031</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">2. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Agarwal, P. K., Nunes, L. D., &amp; Blunt, J. R. (2021). Retrieval practice consistently benefits student learning: A systematic review of applied research in schools and classrooms. Educational Psychology Review, 33, 1409–1453. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10648-021-09595-9</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">3. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Anki. (n.d.). Anki: Powerful, intelligent flashcards. https://apps.ankiweb.net/ [Non-peer-reviewed]</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">4. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Artigue, M., &amp; Trouche, L. (2021). Revisiting the French didactic tradition through technological lenses. Mathematics, 9(6), 629. https://doi.org/10.3390/math9060629</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">5. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Dunlosky, J., Rawson, K. A., Marsh, E. J., Nathan, M. J., &amp; Willingham, D. T. (2013). Improving students’ learning with effective learning techniques: Promising directions from cognitive and educational psychology. Psychological Science in the Public Interest, 14(1), 4–58. https://doi.org/10.1177/1529100612453266</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">6. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Lyle, K. B., Bego, C. R., Hopkins, R. F., Hieb, J. L., &amp; Ralston, P. A. S. (2020). How the amount and spacing of retrieval practice affect the short- and long-term retention of mathematics knowledge. Educational Psychology Review, 32(1), 277–295. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10648-019-09489-x</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">7. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Lyle, K. B., Bego, C. R., Ralston, P. A. S., &amp; Immekus, J. C. (2022). Spaced retrieval practice imposes desirable difficulty in calculus learning. Educational Psychology Review, 34, 1799–1812. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10648-022-09677-2</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">8. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Musial, M., Pradère, F., &amp; Tricot, A. (2011). Prendre en compte les apprentissages lors de la conception d’un scénario pédagogique. Recherche &amp; formation, 68, 15–30. https://doi.org/10.4000/rechercheformation.1483</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">9. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Murray, E., Horner, A. J., &amp; Göbel, S. M. (2025). A meta-analytic review of the effectiveness of spacing and retrieval practice for mathematics learning. Educational Psychology Review, 37, 75. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10648-025-10035-1</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">10. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Pashler, H., Bain, P. M., Bottge, B. A., Graesser, A., Koedinger, K., McDaniel, M., &amp; Metcalfe, J. (2007). Organizing instruction and study to improve student learning (NCER 2007-2004). Institute of Education Sciences, U.S. Department of Education. https://ies.ed.gov/ncee/wwc/Docs/PracticeGuide/20072004.pdf</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">11. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Riopel, M., &amp; McMullin, S. O. (2021). Effets d’espacement et de répétition en contexte scolaire. Neuroéducation, 7(1), 13–19. https://doi.org/10.24046/neuroed.20210701.13</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">12. </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:t>Rohrer, D., &amp; Taylor, K. (2007). The shuffling of mathematics problems improves learning. Instructional Science, 35(6), 481–498. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11251-007-9015-8</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>SECTION L — FOOTER NOTE</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:rPr><w:b/><w:color w:val="2E405B"/></w:rPr><w:t xml:space="preserve">FOOTER_NOTE: </w:t></w:r><w:r><w:rPr><w:i/></w:rPr><w:t>What lasts in a learner’s hands rarely arrives all at once.</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:r><w:br w:type="page"/></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr><w:pStyle w:val="Heading1"/></w:pPr><w:r><w:t>ALPHA TOUCH CHECKLIST</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Alpha Proof — real, verifiable source cited with finding gloss</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Honesty Protocol — Limitations present in Field Notes AND Tool</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Alpha Question — open, one sentence, meets all criteria</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Complexity Ladder — language calibrated to Discover</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Regional Lens — non-English / French didactics source present in Quick Reads or main feature</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Practitioner Voice — concrete, classroom-grounded language in Field Notes</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Glossary Linked — glossary term connects directly to main feature topic</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Didactic Frame — all 3 lenses (Mathematical / Pedagogical / Epistemological) present</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:p><w:pPr/><w:r><w:t>☑ Word count: 2132 words — within 1,800–2,800 range</w:t></w:r></w:p><w:sectPr w:rsidR="00FC693F" w:rsidRPr="0006063C" w:rsidSect="00034616"><w:headerReference w:type="default" r:id="rId9"/><w:footerReference w:type="default" r:id="rId10"/><w:pgSz w:w="12240" w:h="15840"/><w:pgMar w:top="1152" w:right="1296" w:bottom="1080" w:left="1296" w:header="504" w:footer="504" w:gutter="0"/><w:cols w:space="720"/><w:docGrid w:linePitch="360"/></w:sectPr></w:body></w:document>